

# Serena Tomassetti

Zürich, Switzerland

**\$ +41 76 728 42 70** 

□ serenatomassetti001@gmail.com

serenatomassetti.com

linkedin.com/in/serena-tomassetti/

### **PERSONAL DATA**

Italian

15th April 1989

C-Permit

#### **SKILLS**

HCI, User Research, User Interface, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Information Architecture, UX Writings, Lean UX, Usability Test.

### **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

Figma, Sketch, Invision, Axure, Balsamiq, Creative Cloud, Zeplin, Google Analytics, Look Back.

### **LANGUAGES**

Italian: native

English: fluent (C1)

German: professional (B2)

### **PASSIONATE ABOUT**

Design, art, photography, skiing, hiking, traveling.

**SUMMARY** 

Resourceful User Experience Designer with broad practice in design and customer experience. I define new product opportunities, promoting a user centered approach across companies. With strong communication and interpersonal skills, I build fruitful relationships with clients and colleagues. I am recognized for critical thinking, accuracy to details, self management and capacity to adapt quickly. I highly value personal development, I am curious, a hungry reader and traveler, with a high interest in technology and innovation.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Contract UX Designer • Muume AG**

Zürich · Dec 2020-Feb 2021

Designed digital interfaces for B2B and B2C softwares in 3 break points. Collaborated closely with Head of Design, project managers and developers. Field Researches. Agile methodology.

# Contract UX Designer • Altopiano Delle Rocche

Zürich · Sep-Nov 2020

Designed touristic mobile app for Altopiano delle Rocche, from research up to the implementation. Collaborated closely with stakeholders and developers. Lean approach.

# **Contract UX Designer • Bar Voce**

Rome • Apr-Jun 2020

Designed digital strategy for Bar Voce's safe restart during the Covid-19 pandemic. Collaborated closely with stakeholders and developers. Lean approach.

### **UX Designer** • Freelance

Zürich · Aug 2019-Present

Designed digital user experiences in various freelance projects.

### Brand Ambassador • Lindt & Sprüngli

Zürich • Sep 2018-Dec 2020

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Sales and customer experience. Collaborated with Marketing bridging observations of customer needs and proposing solutions. Support on Store Layout, stock and Visual Merchandising.

### **Promoter • M.Prestige Promotions**

Zürich · Sep 2017-Aug 2018

Identification of customer needs and behaviour. Target sales for YSL, Dior, Chanel and customer experience. Trained on customer psychology and behavior from Brand Managers.

# Travel Designer & Booking Agent • Ed è subito Viaggi

Rome • Sep 2017-Aug 2018

Designed tailored travel experiences, established long-term customer loyalty and returning customers. Identification of customer needs, customer experience and support.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **User Experience Nanodegree · Udacity**

Spring 2020

Created an end-to-end digital user experience ready to be handed off for development.

• User research for qualitative and quantitative data • Analysis and Synthesis of collected data • Design Sprint • Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype • Style guide and Design library • Usability test and Iterations.

# **User Experience Bootcamp • Interaction Design Foundation**

2019-2020

Designed a Project Management Web app through 1 to 1 mentorship sessions and guidance.

• User Research • Design Sprint • Sitemap • Low and High fidelity wireframes and prototype • Style guide and Design library.

### Bachelor of Art • University of L'Aquila, Italy

2008-2013

Cultural and Environmental Heritage.

### Erasmus Exchange • University of Zagreb, Croatia

2012-2013

Master's Thesis in History of Architecture.

### **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

- UX Management: Strategy and Tactics, Interaction Design Foundation, 2021.
- Information Visualization: Getting dashboards right, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Gamification: Creating addictive user experiences, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Affordances: Designing intuitive user interfaces, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Accessibility: How to design for all, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Emotional Design: How to make products people will love, Interaction Design Foundation, 2020.
- Agile Software Development, University of Minnesota, 2020
- Human Computer Interaction- HCI, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- UI Design Patterns for succesful software, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20
- User Research Methods and Best Practises, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Mobile UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Design Thinking, Interaction Design Foundation, 2019-20.
- Fundamentals of Graphic Design, typography and storytelling, Californian University of Arts, 2019.
- Store Layout & Visual Merchandising, London University of Arts, 2018
- Travel Experience Design, CTS, 2014.